现代机器人是非常精确的机器。它们可以用于例如将芯片放置在其上
Modern robots are very precise machines. They can be used for example to place chips onto
电路板精度高，速度快。但他们如何实际做到这一点呢？
circuit boards with great precision and at very great speed. But how do they actually do that?
永远不会直接测量机器人末端执行器的位置。我们做了什么
The position of the robot’s end effector is never directly measured. What we do instead
测量各种关节角度，我们使用正向运动模型来确定
is measure the various joint angles and we use a forward kinematic model to determine
机器人末端执行器的位置。
the position of the robot’s end effector.
我们假设我们知道机器人工具尖端所在位置的笛卡尔坐标
We assume that we know the position in Cartesian coordinates of where the robot’s tool tip
需要去，然后设计一个采用该工具的控制器是一件简单的事情
needs to go and then it’s a simple matter of designing a controller that takes the tool
提示从它到达的地方。这是基本原则
tip from where it is to where it needs to go. And this is the fundamental principle
支撑着今天所有的现代机器人。它们非常精确，它们非常精确
underpinning all modern robots today. They are incredibly precise, they have got very
精确的传感器，他们有非常好的运动模型，他们能够移动
accurate sensors, they’ve got very good kinematic models, and they are able to move
它需要在工作场所进行的工具提示。
the tool tip where it needs to go in the workplace.
让我们现在考虑这种机器人工具定位方法可能出现的问题。
Lets consider now what can go wrong with this approach to robot tool positioning.
首先;因为工具的位置是由关节传感器和运动学计算的
Firstly; because the position of the tool is computed from joint sensors and kinematic
模型，如果任何传感器中存在错误，如果运动学中存在错误
models, if there are errors in any of the sensors, if there’s an error in the kinematic
模型，或者在我们认为机器人的基础是什么的时候可能存在错误，然后是
model, or perhaps there is an error in where we think the base of the robot is, then the
机器人工具尖端的位置将出错。
position of the robot tool tip is going to be in error.
也许芯片相对于电路板的位置存在误差
Perhaps there is an error in the location of the chip relative to the board, or perhaps
电路板相对于机器人坐标系的位置存在误差。
there is an error in the position of the board with respect to the robot’s coordinate frame.
最后，运动控制系统可能存在错误。它无法驾驶
Finally there could be an error in the motion control system. It’s not able to drive the
机器人工具提示到它需要去的地方。
robot tool tip to where it needs to go to.
尽管如此，在制造机器人的悠久历史中，这些问题已基本得到解决。
Nevertheless, over the long history of manufacturing robots these problems have largely been ironed out.
这种传统的机器人定位方法有其后果。作为一个开始
There is a consequence for this traditional approach to robot positioning. For a start
我们需要在每个关节上都有非常精确的传感器。机器人链接需要
we need to have very very accurate sensors on each of the joints. The robot links need
非常精确地加工，因此它们反映了嵌入在中的运动模型
to be very very accurately machined so they reflect the kinematic model embedded in the
软件。机器人链接也需要非常坚硬，以便机器人改变它
software. The robot links also need to be very stiff so that as the robot changes its
配置链接在重力的影响下不会弯曲和变形。制作它们
configuration the links don’t bend and deform under the influence of gravity. To make them
僵硬，我们必须使用大量的金属，这使他们沉重。然后为了机器人
stiff we have to use a lot of metal, which makes them heavy. In order for the robot then
要快速行动，我们需要拥有更强大的电机。
to move quickly we need to have much more powerful motors.
所有这些问题都推高了现代精密工业机器人的成本。
All of these issues drive up the cost of the modern precise industrial robot.
所以我们假设我们有一个机器人并且它非常精确。我们如何实际使用它？
So lets assume we have a robot and that it is really precise. How do we actually put it to use?
为机器人做有用的东西，它正在使用的对象-它的工件
For the robot to do useful things the object that it’s working with — its work piece
-还必须精确定位。如果机器人能够到x，y，z位置
— must also be precisely positioned. If the robot is able to go to position x,y,z
在一小部分毫米之内，那么它正在使用的对象也需要
within a small fraction of a millimetre, then the object that it’s working with also needs
以相同的准确度定位。当一个机器人安装在一个大的工厂
to be positioned with that same level of accuracy. When a robot is installed in a factory a large
工程量涉及创造我们称之为夹具和固定装置。这些是
amount of engineering is involved in creating what we call jigs and fixtures. These are
将机器人的工件固定在一个非常精确的位置的设备
pieces of equipment that hold the robot’s work piece at a very precise location in the
机器人的工作空间。因此，当机器人使用其精度到达特定坐标时
robot’s workspace. So when the robot uses its precision to reach to a particular coordinate
它需要合作的东西就在那里。
the thing that it needs to work with is there.
下一个问题是机器人需要知道对象在其工作空间内的位置。
Next issue is that the robot needs to know the position of the object within its workspace.
我们需要非常准确地测量它。在实践中，发生的是工件
We need to measure that very very accurately. In practice what happens is the work piece
在工作区中的一个非常一致的位置，我们手动调整机器人的位置
is held at a very consistent location in the workspace and we manually adjust the robot’s
工具尖端位置来完成任务。在这个特定的图片中操作员正在做
tool tip position to achieve the task. In this particular picture the operator doing
这个。操作员手里拿着什么叫教导。它是
this. The operator is holding in his hand what’s called a teach pendant. It’s a
按钮上盖着一个大盒子，通过推动这些按钮，他可以驱动机器人
large box covered in buttons, and by pushing these buttons he is able to drive the robot’s
工具提示到工作区内的所需位置。
tool tip to the required location within the workspace.
这种方法的替代方案完全依赖于机器人的固有精度，
An alternative to this approach which relies totally on the inherent precision of the robot,
是让机器人使用其传感器-例如模仿功能的摄像机
is to have the robot use its sensors — for instance cameras which mimic the function
我们的眼睛-为了引导它执行任务。而这正是我们所做的;
of our eyes — in order to guide it to perform the task. And that’s exactly what we do;
如果我想拿起这个订书机，我会用我的眼睛引导我的手，以便距离
if I want to pick up this stapler I use my eyes to guide my hand so that the distance
在我的指尖和订书机之间变为零。同样，如果我想执行任务
between my fingertips and the stapler become zero. Similarly if I want to perform a task
就像把钥匙放进锁里一样，我再一次用眼睛引导我的手，以便把它的尖端
like putting a key into a lock, I again use my eyes to guide my hand so that the tip of
钥匙进入锁的桶。
the key enters the barrel of the lock.
这是实践中的一个例子。这是我自己的博士研究方法的一些工作
Here’s an example of this in practice. This is some work from my own PhD research way
在这里，机器人手臂被编程为恒定地向上和向下移动
back in 1993. Here the robot arm is programmed to move upwards and downwards at constant
速度，但机器人的水平运动由线的形状控制
velocity, but the horizontal motion of the robot is controlled by the shape of the line
这是在观察。所以在这个意义上，机器人正在对世界上的事物作出反应。
that it is observing. So in this sense the robot is reacting to what is in the world.
所以我可以在机器人前放置任何形状的线条，机器人手臂会移动和跟踪
So I can put any shaped line in front of the robot, and the robot arm would move and trace
沿着那条线的路径。
a path along that line.
在这个更复杂的例子中，机器人正在携带一个摄像头，它正在努力保持
In this more complex example, the robot is carrying a camera, and it’s trying to keep
一个位于其视野中心的物体。现在对象在转盘上，所以它是
an object in the centre of its field of view. Now the object is on a turntable so it’s
以相当复杂的方式移动。事实上，它并没有以恒定的速度移动，而是在加速，
moving in quite a complex way. In fact it’s not moving at a constant velocity, it is accelerating,
在这里，我们看到机器人捕捉物体，锁定它并将其保持在中心
and here we see the robot capturing the object, locking onto it, and holding it in the centre
它的视野。
of its field of view.
然后应用相同的技术来跟踪已投入的乒乓球
The same technique was then applied to tracking a ping-pong ball, which has been thrown in
从场景的一侧，这是慢动作。最终机器人注意到了
from one side of the scene, and this is in slow motion. Eventually the robot notices
乒乓球，锁定它，并开始以保持的方式移动相机
the ping-pong ball, locks onto it, and starts to move the camera in such a way as to keep
乒乓球更接近现场的中心。所以它正在跟踪乒乓球
the ping-pong ball closer to the centre of the scene. So it’s tracking the ping-pong
球在太空中移动。而且这是实时的。我们看到了乒乓球
ball as it is moving through space. And here it is in real time. We see the ping-pong ball
动作非常快。
moves very very quickly.
当我正在考虑使用感觉来控制移动机器人时，这是一些更古老的工作
Here is some more old work when I was looking at controlling a mobile robot using the sense
愿景。所以这个特殊的机器人顶部有一个全方位的摄像头，并且
of vision. So this particular robot has got an omni-directional camera on the top, and
在那个全方位的摄像机视图中，我们可以找到道路的边缘。这是非常的
in that omni-directional camera view we can find the edges of the roadway. It’s a very
明亮的混凝土路面与绿草和棕色泥土之间的明显边界
distinct boundary between the bright concrete road and the green grass and the brown dirt
在路的两边。我们想要做的就是让机器人保持运动
on either side of the road. What we want to do then is to keep the robot so it’s moving
我们能够在视觉上观察到的道路两个边界之间的中间位置。
midway between the two boundaries of the road that we are able to observe visually.
这是另一个涉及移动机器人的例子。在这种情况下，机器人正在使用它
Here is another example involving a mobile robot. In this case the robot is using its
视觉信息-再次来自全方位摄像机-以固定的方式定位自己
visual information — again from an omni-directional camera — to position itself with a fixed
相对于交通锥的姿势偏移。所以，如果我选择交通锥并移动
pose offset with respect to the traffic cone. So if I pick the traffic cone up and moved
它到另一个地方，机器人会移动，以保持固定的姿势
it to another place, the robot would move in order to maintain that fixed pose with
对交通锥的尊重。因此机器人不会相对于坐标进行导航
respect to the traffic cone. So the robot is not navigating with respect to a coordinate
附加到此位置的框架，它相对于其环境中的对象或特征进行导航。
frame attached to this location, it is navigating with respect to an object or a feature in its environment.
这是一辆车，一辆叉车，前面有一个挂钩，正在尝试
This is a vehicle, a forklift truck, and it’s got a hook on the front, and it’s trying
将钩子穿过坩埚的把手。叉车上有一个摄像头
to put that hook through the handle of the crucible. There is a camera on the forklift
卡车，它往下看并用它来识别手柄的位置和控制
truck and it is looking down and using that to identify where the handle is, and controlling
位置-车辆的路径-当它接近坩埚时。在这个特别的
the position — the path of the vehicle — as it approaches the crucible. In this particular
我们不得不在坩埚上添加一些标记，以帮助机器人车辆实现可靠性
case we had to add some markers to the crucible to help the robot vehicle achieve the reliable
拾起。你现在看到的是一部延时电影。我们
pickup. What you see now is a time-lapse movie. We
整整一天都进行了这个实验。在一天的过程中照明条件
ran this experiment over a whole day. Over the course of the day the lighting conditions
改变了：云来了又走了;阴影来了又走了。它显示了整体的稳健性
changed: clouds came and went; shadows came and went. It showed the overall robustness
这种基于愿景的战略的可靠性和可靠性。机器人没有任何知识
and reliability of this vision-based strategy. The robot didn’t have any knowledge of where
坩埚是;它只是移动以减少钩尖和手柄之间的区域。
the crucible was; it just moved to reduce the area between the tip of the hook and the handle.
这是一种非常相似的技术，在这种情况下应用于水下。所以这个水下
Here’s a very similar technique, in this case applied underwater. So this underwater
机器人有一对立体相机，它在海床上方保持恒定的高度。
robot has got a stereo camera pair and it’s maintaining a constant height above the seabed.